Guide to the Enoch A. Bryan Papers 1843-1989
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
- Series 3. Materials acquired from President's Office, circa 1958
  - Series 3.1: Speeches, essays, etc.
    - History--U.S. and Pacific Northwest
      - N.W.T. (Northwest Territory) (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - Notes re: publication of Orient meets Occident (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - Notebook re: United State History (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - Untitled, re: Pacific Northwest (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - History of Washington Committee (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - Rothrock and Wyandotte Cave (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - A Bird's Glimpse of the Pacific Northwest (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - Radio Program: Four Short Chapters in History of the Pacific Northwest (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - The New Northwest (Box 7, Folder 53)
      - The Gold Rush of 60s (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Holland, E. O.
      - Paper, re: honorary degree for Holland (Box 8, Folder 54)
      - The New WSC President, for NW Journal of Education A new Regime (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Idaho
      - The Public School Situation in Idaho (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - The Idaho System of Education (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - History of Development of Property (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - The Idaho System and the State University (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - Higher Education Institutions in Idaho (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - Idaho High Schools (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - Untitled Speech (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - The Problem of the Idaho (illegible) about university (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - Untitled, to editor of Idaho Alumnus (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - Untitled, re: talk to Idaho Judges (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - Stenographic report .. Bryan's testimony to legislature (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - Untitled, with corresp. to faculty of Univ. of Idaho (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Irrigation and Water
      - Untitled, re: riparian rights (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - Irrigation Committee (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - Transfer of Possession and Management of Canal (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - The Greatest Good to the Greatest Number (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - The American Falls Dam and Irrigation Project (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - Cooperation Between Smith-Hughes and Boys-Girls Club Work (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - Reclamation (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - The Rural Church and the Automobile (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - The Fifty-Cent Dollar and the Schools (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - The Columbia Project and the State of Idaho (Box 8, Folder 56)
      - Too Wet or Too Dry (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Labor
      - To the Editor of the Pacific Farmer (Box 8, Folder 57)
      - The Right to Strike (Box 8, Folder 57)
      - A Study in Interest (Box 8, Folder 57)
      - Then and Now (Box 8, Folder 57)
      - Collective Bargaining (Box 8, Folder 57)
      - Unemployment (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Land-Grant Colleges and Universities
      - The Spirit of the Land-Grant Institutions, by Kerr, Davenport, Bryan and Thompson (Box 8, Folder 58)
      - A Land-Grant College (MSS for Americana Illustrated, 1940) (Box 8, Folder 58)
      - Untitled; critique of unidentified paper re: Land-grant Colleges (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - Legends
      - A College Ghost (Box 8, Folder 59)
      - The Legend of the Black Cat (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Literature
      - Note, re: Chaucer and Oxford Student (Box 8, Folder 60)
      - Untitled, re: Ralph Waldo Emerson (Box 8, Folder 60)
      - Statues at Large transcription of Labor Law London, 1587 (Box 8, Folder 60)
      - Sartor Resartis (Box 8, Folder 60)
      - Scotland, the Scotch and Robert Burns (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Man and his Characteristics: Moral Philosophy
      - Baccalaureate Address -- Choice of a Life's Work (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - Untitled, re: the "age" and its prospects (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - A Word from President Emeritus E. A. Bryan (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - An Address by Frank Kreager (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - Untitled, re: Our Age (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - For a Class Graduating from the High School (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - The Function of Work in Education (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - The Tripos of Christian Character (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - Roman Education and Roman Character (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - Life's Work (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - The Buried Talent (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - Some Traits of Roman Character (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - Phi Kappa Phi Address, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - The Spirit of Cain (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - Baccalaureate Address, Vincennes University, 1891 (Box 8, Folder 61)
      - The Ethics of the Dust (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - The Realm of Choice (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - An Easter Meditation: If a Man Die, Shall He Live Again? (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - Character (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - Continuity and the Persistence of Character (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - The Truth Shall Spring out of the Earth (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - The Choice of Life's Work (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - Be not Overcome of Evil but Overcome Evil with God (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - Human Responsibility (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - Shall the Instruction and Curriculum of the Public High School be prescribed by the College and University Characteristics (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - Are the Schools Better (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - The Buried Talent (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - The Unused Talent (Box 8, Folder 62)
      - Limitation (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - People and Memorials
      - Memorial Address: Samuel G. Cosgrove (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - The Other Concord and Emerson (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Tribute to Thomas Neill (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Funeral Address for Regent Brown (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Review of The Trend of the American University by David Starr Jordan (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Ben Holladay (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Henry C. Wallace and the Iowa Group (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Funeral of William D. Foster (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Appreciation of Dr. W. J. Spillman (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Memorial in honor of the late Dr. W.J. Spillman (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Three Men from Missouri (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Inauguration of Dr. A.H. Upham (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - Memoirs Relative to Doctor Richard Owen (Box 8, Folder 63)
      - The University of Birmingham (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Prices and Cost of Living
      - Untitled, re: Pullman Housewives and cost of living (Box 8, Folder 64)
      - The Message of America (Box 8, Folder 64)
      - Will Prices Fall (Box 8, Folder 64)
      - Inflation and Contraction (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Religion
      - An Easter Meditation (Box 8, Folder 65)
      - God's Training for Leadership, by Lemuel Moss, 1881 (Box 8, Folder 65)
      - The Tripos of Christian Character (Box 8, Folder 65)
      - The Gospel of the Kingdom of God (Box 8, Folder 65)
      - The Rural Church (Box 8, Folder 65)
      - The Master Teacher (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - School Lands: Construction
      - Ways and Means for Construction (Box 8, Folder 66)
      - The Function and Purpose of the College (Box 8, Folder 66)
      - Experiment Station at Puyallup (Box 8, Folder 66)
      - Future Constructional Development (Box 8, Folder 66)
      - College Lands (Box 8, Folder 66)
      - Brewster Lands (Box 8, Folder 66)
      - Scientific School Funds (Box 8, Folder 66)
      - The State Board of Control (Box 8, Folder 66)
      - Cost Plus (Box 8, Folder 66)
      - The School Lands (Box 8, Folder 66)
      - The Scientific School Lands Belonging to the State College (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Senate of United States - Declaration of Candidacy (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - Stories
      - The Lolo Trail (Box 8, Folder 68)
      - Blood Will Tell (Box 8, Folder 68)
      - A Deer Hunt (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - State Legislature
      - Pertinent Facts (re: teacher certification) (Box 8, Folder 69)
      - Untitled, re: Prohibition and temperance (Box 8, Folder 69)
      - Untitled, re: Institutions of Higher Education and the Repeal of the Special Mill Tax (Box 8, Folder 69)
      - Untitled, re: Teacher Training (Box 8, Folder 69)
      - Statement Relative to House Bill 345 (US Congress) (Box 8, Folder 69)
      - Will the Next Legislature be Penny Wise? (Box 8, Folder 69)
      - Copy of letter to Re. LaFollette, re: Lever Bill (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Taxation
      - Taxation for the Support of Public Schools (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - Programme at Olympia (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - The Method of Adjusting the Mill Tax for the State College and the University (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - Notes on a State-wide Tax Franchise (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - The Millage (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - A Defense of High Taxes (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - The Fixed Tax for the Support of Higher Educational Institutions, Commonly Known as the Mill Tax (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - The Mill Tax (in three parts) (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - Untitled, re: the mill tax (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - A Mill Tax (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - The Mill Tax Law (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - Untitled, re: Governor's budget and mill tax changes (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - Untitled, re: proposed budgets (Box 9, Folder 70)
      - Untitled, re: tax changes (Box 9, Folder 70)
    - Transportation
      - Two Railway Systems Major N.W. Builders (Box 9, Folder 71)
      - Transportation in the Pacific Northwest (two parts) (Box 9, Folder 71)
      - Rosario in the Argentine (Box 9, Folder 71)
      - A Barge System in the Columbia (Box 9, Folder 71)
      - Steamboat at the Bottom on Lake Pend Oreille (Box 9, Folder 71)
      - Notes of J.G. Woodworth, NPRR (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - Washington State College
      - Foundation and Purpose of the College (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - The Amended Charter of 1891 (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Twenty-one Years of Progress (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Need of an Armory (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Expansion (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled Notes, re: Overview of WSC (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - To the Members of the Legislature (re: name change) (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - A Word from President Emeritus Bryan (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: preparatory department (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - To the Editor of the Spokesman Review (re: budget) (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - To the Member of the Joint Appropriations Committee (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - To the Editor of the Post Intelligencer (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: freshmen in athletics (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: general concept of college (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Suggestion (re: changing office of Dean of Faculty) (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Be It Enacted ... (Draft bill for purchase of a farm) (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - [To] The Seatttle Post Intelligencer (re: Bryan's last day as president) (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: budgets and appropriations (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - The Message of Welcome ... (to E.O. Holland) (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: Tau Kappa Epsilon petition (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - A Message (re: 45th Anniversary of WSC) (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Services of the State College (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Fair Play (re: appropriations) (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Cost of the State College of Washington to the Taxpayer (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: overview of WSC (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Functions of the State College (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Memorandum of the Closing Remarks Made on the Graduation of Class of 1937 (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - To the Members of the Joint Appropriations Committee (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Dear Sir (re: overview of college) (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Liberal Arts Faculties at the State College of Washington (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - A brief resume of the facts.. re: charter of college (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - To the Editor of the Tribune (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: accomplishments of the college (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled re: Smith-Lever and Extension (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Fragments, re: college, legal status, etc. (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Introduction .. (re manual training) (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled reminiscence, re: Gov. Rogers and education (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: history of college legislation (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: early history of college From 1910 files, re: Home Economics (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: opening college, fall, 1916 Outline of Information (completed form) (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: early history of college The State Agricultural College and School of Science (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: veterinary program Untitled, re: review of year activities (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - To the Editor of the Montana Farmer (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: college church (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled (Does College Lessen Business Success chance?) (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Committee of Experts Commended (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Should the Work of the State College be limited? (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Engineering Departments (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Reminiscences of the State College of Washington (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Getting Under Way (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Radio Talk: The Founders of the College, Charles Vancouver Piper, Sofus Nelson, Elton Fulmer, W.J. Spillman (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - The Research Council (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Radio Talk; Faculty Members--Past and Present (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Radio Alumni Notes (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Reminiscence of Early Pullman and the College (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - The Department of Elementary Science (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - History of the Gavel and its Presentation (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - The Case of the Agricultural College (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Reminiscences of Early History of the College and Pullman (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Historical Sketch of the Development of Engineer Education (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Untitled, re: Music and Fine Arts (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - The New Spirit (Box 9, Folder 72)
      - Press Releases by Ashlock (Box 9, Folder 73)
      - Fragments--Notes-- probably an annual report (Box 9, Folder 74)
      - Conditions of Employment (Box 9, Folder 74)
      - The Old College Fund (Box 9, Folder 74)
    - Various Papers, Speeches -- Undifferentiated
      - Fragment--reminiscences of 1893 (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Untitled, re: withdrawal of resignation (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Untitled, re: Grayville reunion, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Introduction to Chinook of 1935 (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Untitled, probably Memorial Day address (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Suggestions to the Social Science Section of the Northwest Scientific Association (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Address to Pullman Kiwanis on Constitution Day (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Prelude (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - The Ethics of Sex (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - The Ethics of Sex--The Family (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - The Family (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - The American's Country Home (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Whither are we Drifting -- The New Rich (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - The Control of the Purse (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Why Laborites and Agrarians Differ Politically (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - German Socialism (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Capitalism (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Washington and the Constitution (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Forefather's Day, 1920 (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Capitalism (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Abraham Lincoln (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - A Word of Greeting from Doctor Bryan (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - List of agricultural competition prizes (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Report of time for week commencing Monday Sep 8 1915 (of Extension service agents?) (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Fragment of a letter, June 8, 1914 (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Report of Veterinary Program, S. B. Nelson, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 75)
      - Untitled, re: Conservation of Natural Resources"(two copies) (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Fragment, re: Railroad land grants (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Untitled, re: Imperialism (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Dear Evergreen, re: European trip (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Editor Tacoma News, (On unfavorable living and"working conditions in home kitchens, by Francis Christien) (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - To the Faculty (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Untitled memo re: stenographic procedures at WSC (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Untitled, re: Boards for State Institutions (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - American Colleges and Universities, two parts (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Copy of Gold Standard Act of 1900 (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Untitled, address to a teacher's association (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Fragment, re: tax receipts (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Untitled, a memo or address to Phi Beta Kappa (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Untitled, re: a case of athletic eligibility (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - The Relation of the Public Lands to the Extinguishment of the First Public Debt (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Principles of the Anarchists (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - The Truth Shall Make You Free (partial 2nd copy) (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Printing and Binding (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Experiment Station (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Enrollment of Students (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - The Permanent vs. the Changeable (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - The Waitsburg Academy (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - The Japs on the Coast (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - The Sick Room, Nurse, and the Public Nurse (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Success--Finding It (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Population (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Letters from Dr. E.A. Bryan (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - The Deanship (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Paternalism (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Good Roads (Box 9, Folder 76)
      - Internationalism (Box 9, Folder 76)
    - Foundation Day speeches (Box 10, Folder 77)
    - Building Dedications (Box 10, Folder 78)
    - Let Us Have Peace, and Peace and War (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Series 3.2: Enoch A. Bryan Personal Correspondence and Papers
    - Agriculture, undated (Box 10, Folder 80)
    - Autobiography, Biography, Letter, 1958 (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - Biennial Estimates, University of Washington, 1909-1911 (Box 10, Folder 82)
    - Biographical Sketch and Letter To Herman J. Deutsch, 1914, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Hattie Williams Bryan, March 10, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - William Lowe Bryan, Photograph, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - Calling Cards, undated (Box 11, Folder 86)
    - Certificate of Appreciation from the Congregation of the United Presbyterian Churches, January 3, 1916 (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - Correspondence Regarding Location of College at Pullman Site, 1891-1899 (Box 11, Folder 88)
    - Correspondence To W. O. Passmore, February 2, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 89)
    - Cost of Education, circa 1916 (Box 11, Folder 90)
    - Degree of Flora Certificate, 1903 (Box 11, Folder 91)
    - Family Photographs, 1931, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 92)
    - Financial Documents (Tax), 1904, 1905, 1910 (Box 11, Folder 93)
    - Honorary Doctor of Laws Degree Diploma, Washington State College, June 3, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 94)
    - Maps of the Northwest, 1890-1916 (Box 11, Folder 95)
    - Memoranda Regarding Choice of Pullman as Site for Agricultural College, undated (Box 11, Folder 96)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1899-1942 (Box 11, Folder 97-99)
    - Official Stamp, undated (Box 11, Folder 100)
    - Phi Kappa Phi Certificate, 1924 (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - Photograph of Home in Vincennes, Indiana, undated (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - Pullman Chamber of Commerce Life Membership Award, 1903 (Box 11, Folder 103)
    - The Quarter-Century Club Menus, 1934, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - Scrapbook, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - Sketch, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 106)
    - Student Expenses, 1915-1916 (Box 11, Folder 107)
    - Twentieth Century Club, 1912 (Box 11, Folder 108)
    - University of Washington, 1911 (Box 11, Folder 109)
- Series 4. Materials acquired with personal papers in Bryan Family, circa 1990
  - Series 4.1. Speeches and essays
    - Political
      - Ladies and Gentlemen, a campaign speech for Senate (Box 12, Folder 110)
      - The Foes of Democracy (Box 12, Folder 110)
    - Early Addresses and Essays
      - The Lost Jewel (Box 12, Folder 110)
      - The Passion of Conquest (Box 12, Folder 110)
      - Public Sentiment (Box 12, Folder 110)
      - The Need of the South (Box 12, Folder 110)
      - The Township Trustee Problem (Box 12, Folder 110)
      - Decoration Day (Box 12, Folder 110)
      - Statesmanship (Box 12, Folder 110)
      - Grayville High School Commencement Materials (denoting possible authorship of some papers by Grayville students) (Box 12, Folder 111)
      - Heredity, Environment and the Will (Box 12, Folder 111)
      - Items--on Pym and Cromwell (Box 12, Folder 111)
      - The Educational Value of Work and Play (Box 12, Folder 111)
      - Abhor That Which is Evil (Box 12, Folder 111)
      - My Confession of Faith (Box 12, Folder 111)
      - Life a Contest; first public oration of E.A. Bryan (Box 12, Folder 111)
      - Health (Box 12, Folder 112)
      - The Need of the South (Box 12, Folder 112)
      - Rain (Box 12, Folder 112)
      - Alcestis of Euripides (translation) (Box 12, Folder 112)
      - Unrequited Merit (Box 12, Folder 112)
    - Addresses and Essays
      - Untitled, to the Matrons Club (Box 12, Folder 113)
      - The Dismissal of President Suzzallo (Box 12, Folder 113)
      - Lines of Experiment Station Work (Box 12, Folder 113)
      - A National System of Education (Box 12, Folder 113)
      - Experiment Station Methods (Box 12, Folder 113)
      - Money (Box 12, Folder 113)
      - The Belles of Bloomington (Box 12, Folder 113)
      - Ignorance and the Ballot in the South (Box 12, Folder 113)
      - Gold (Box 12, Folder 114)
      - Radio Talk- Founders of the State College, Elton Fulmer (Box 12, Folder 114)
      - The Realm of Choice (Ohio University, 1930) (Box 12, Folder 114)
      - Financial History - U.S. (Box 12, Folder 114)
      - Untitled re: Financial History (Box 12, Folder 114)
    - Literature
      - If a Man Die, Shall He Live Again? (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - Platonism and Christianity (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - On the Study of Biography (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - A True Ghost Story (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - Shakespeare and His Contemporaries in Literature, Religion, Politics, Arts, and Discoveries (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - Prelude in Plays (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - George Washington: The Image and the Man (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - Situations of the Play (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - In a Balcony (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - The Life and Art of Maude Adams (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - On Writing Essays (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - Anael (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - Character Sketches from Virgin Soil (Box 12, Folder 115)
      - Literature Prelude on Stage, Prologue in Heaven (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - Browning's Creed on Art as Revealed in (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - Old Pictures in Florence (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - The Good Old Pope (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - Ibsen's Conception of the Ideal Man As Revealed in Brand (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - Gunlang, the Mother (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - The Harpies (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - The Roman Matron (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - Language and the English language (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - The Princes: Tennyson and the Emancipation of Women (Box 12, Folder 116)
      - The Spirit of the Forest (Box 13, Folder 117)
      - Study Questions for A Souls Tragedy (Box 13, Folder 117)
      - Browning's Paraccelsus (Box 13, Folder 117)
      - Dante's Hell compared with Milton's (Box 13, Folder 117)
      - A Soul's Tragedy: Browning (Box 13, Folder 117)
      - Life of Elizabeth Barnett Browning (Box 13, Folder 117)
      - Prometheus Unbound (Box 13, Folder 117)